Aarush Aitha

School Address: 8151 Village Pkwy Dublin, CA 94568

School Phone: 925-833-3300 My Email: aarush3002@google.com



Objective

I desire to be a cyber defense expert, specializing in software and computer science.

Colleges of Interest: Carnegie Mellon, Cal Tech, UC Berkeley, UC San Diego

Majors of Interest: Cyber Security, EECS, Computer Science, Software Engineering, Computer Programming

Education

Dublin High School 2017-2021 (Expected Diploma: Advanced Scholar)

- Sophomore Year (current GPA: 4.1)
 - o Introduction to Structured C++ (A supplemental summer class)
 - Honors Principles of Engineering, AP Chemistry, AP Statistics, AP European History, Spanish
- Freshman Year
 - o Honors Chemistry, Trigonometry/Precalculus, Computer Science/Software Engineering

Work Experience

Tutor at Pleasanton-North Kumon (Supervised and Recommended by Hester Hing)

Dublin, CA - December 2017 to present

- Grading work and tutoring elementary to middle school age students
 - Earned approximately 10 dollars an hour.
 - Since I want to become a cyber defender, teaching will increase my skill in lecturing and teaching at college-level classes.

Extracurricular activities

Dublin High CyberSecurity (2017 - present)

- Sophomore Year
 - o Captaining a new team of 6 members
 - Consistently placing in the top 5 percent in the nation
- Freshman Year
 - Captained a team of 6 members
 - o Currently in top 10% in the nation (Platinum Division)

Gael Force Robotics Club (2017 - present)

- Sophomore Year
 - o Member of competitive team 5327X
 - Learned important skills about programming using PROS (C++ and Java software)
- Freshman Year
 - o Member of the Development Team, 5327D (discontinued)
 - Volunteered for the "Battle of Bay" tournament hosted at Dublin High School
 - Developed skills in VEX approved C programming

Volunteer

Habitat For Humanity

Tijuana, Mexico - November 17 2017 to November 22 2017

Designed and built houses for Pablo, Mario, and Adrian in Tijuana (Northern Mexico). Stayed in an
orphanage and helped with chores and cooking with 6 other families.

Tech Support, Mentor, and Emcee at CoderDojo

TriValley Coderdojo - June 2015 - present

- Mentored students in Scratch, HTML, and CSS (Web Design)
- Helped with Lightning Talks (very quick presentations), fixed audio and video-graphical problems
- As of October 2018, member of the Teen Leadership group for TriValley CoderDojo

Skills

- Have knowledge of Java, Python, Command Line, HTML, CSS, C++, and JavaScript
- Certified by the Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music (ABRSM) Piano, Level 6 of 8
- Certified Black Belt (Degree II) by Pallen's Martial Arts Karate dojo.